A Finding Aid to the Florence Arquin Papers, 1923-1985, in the Archives of American Art AAA.arquflor
Archives of American Art
Florence Arquin papers
1923-1985
AAA.arquflor
Archives of American Art
8.3 Linear feet
The papers of Florence Arquin measure 8.3 linear feet and date from 1923 to 1985. The papers document Arquin's career as a painter, photographer, educator, writer, and critic through biographical material, correspondence, writings, teaching and project files, printed material, photographs, artwork, and scrapbooks. Additionally, the papers relate to her personal relationships with her husband Samuel Williams and friends, Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo. Teaching and project files include material from Arquin's work with the Federal Art Project at the Art Institute of Chicago and as director of the U.S. State Department's Kodachrome Slide Project, which was part of an effort to provide educational agencies with visual aids to support Latin American Studies.
Arquin, Florence
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1939-1962 (0.4 linear feet; Box 1, 11)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1940-1985 (0.8 linear feet; Box 1-2)
Series 3: Writings and Notes, 1929-circa 1964 (2.0 linear feet; Box 2-4)
Series 4: Teaching and Project Files, 1930-1963 (1.4 linear feet; Box 4-5)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1923-1964 (1.8 linear feet; Box 5-7, 11)
Series 6: Photographs, 1929-circa 1960 (0.7 linear feet; Box 7, 11)
Series 7: Artwork, circa 1940-circa 1950 (2 folders; Box 7, 11)
Series 8: Scrapbooks, 1935-1956 (0.9 linear feet; Box 8-10)
Biographical/Historical note
Painter, photographer, educator, writer, and critic, Florence Arquin (1900-1974) was active in Chicago, Illinois. She was widely known for her expertise in the field of Latin American Studies and had a close relationship with Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera. From 1935 to 1939 she worked as administrator for the Federal Art Project in Illinois and joined the Art Institute of Chicago in 1939 to develop education programs aimed at secondary school students.
Florence Arquin was born in 1900 in New York City. She graduated from the Art Institute of Chicago where she studied art education. After, she undertook post graduate studies at the National University of Mexico. In the early 1940s Arquin traveled to Mexico to paint, where she developed friendships with Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo. In 1943 a solo exhibition of her paintings at the Benjamin Franklin Library in Mexico City was highly praised by Rivera in the catalog introduction. Arquin's book Diego Rivera: The Shaping of an Artist, 1889-1921 about the artist's formative years, was published by the University of Oklahoma Press in 1971.
Arquin traveled extensively in South America, the United States, and Europe throughout her life. From 1945 to 1951 she traveled to Brazil, Bolivia, Peru, and Ecuador as Director of the Kodachrome Slide Project under the sponsorship of the Department of State. Arquin photographed aspects of life and culture and gave lectures at bi-national cultural institutions throughout those countries and in the United States. The project was part of an effort to provide educational agencies with visual aids in the field of Latin American studies.
Under another State Department grant, duplicates of Arquin's photographs were then made available for sale to institutions and individuals interested in the field of Latin American studies. The Metropolitan Museum of Art assumed responsibility for publicity, sale, and distribution of the slides from 1950 to 1955. Although few sales originated through the sales office of the Museum, Arquin managed to generate sales through her own efforts. In 1961 she applied for another grant to take control of the original slides and to add slides that she had taken on other visits to Latin America, Morocco, Spain, Portugal, and other European countries since then.
Florence Arquin died in 1974.
Conditions Governing Access note
The Florence Arquin papers are owned by the Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution. Literary rights as possessed by the donor have been dedicated to public use for research, study, and scholarship. The collection is subject to all copyright laws.
Existence and Location of Copies note
The collection was digitized in 2015 and is available via the Archives of American Art's website.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was donated to the Archives of American Art by Samuel Williams, Arquin's husband, in 1991.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of Florence Arquin measure 8.3 linear feet and date from 1923 to 1985. The papers document Arquin's career as a painter, photographer, educator, writer, and critic through biographical material, correspondence, writings, teaching and project files, printed material, photographs, artwork, and scrapbooks. Additionally, the papers relate to her personal relationships with her husband Samuel Williams and friends, Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo. Teaching and project files include material from Arquin's work with the Federal Art Project at the Art Institute of Chicago and as director of the U.S. State Department's Kodachrome Slide Project, which was part of an effort to provide educational agencies with visual aids to support Latin American Studies.
Biographical materials include awards, biographical sketches and resumes, travel papers, identification cards, and ten address books.
The bulk of correspondence is comprised of letters written by Florence Arquin to her husband, Samuel Williams. These letters discuss her trips to Mexico in the 1940s, her role in the Kodachrome Slide Project, and her friendships with fellow artists Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, and others. Also found are copies of letters from Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera to Florence Arquin.
Writings and notes include extensive research notes, notebooks, and notecards by Florence Arquin, primarly on Latin American art and culture. Also found is a draft of Arquin's work on Diego Rivera, Diego Rivera (1886-1957): The Shaping of an Artist (Early Period--1889-1921). Writings by others include a draft of a foreword by Diego Rivera, and writings by Jose de Souza Pedreira, and Hilla Rebay.
Teaching and project files include materials from Arquin's time teaching at the Art Institute of Chicago, her work with the the Federal Art Project at the Art Institute of Chicago and the Kodachrome Slide Project. Teaching files are scattered and include student papers, class outlines, and a lecture. The Federal Art Project at the Art Institute of Chicago files include a proposal and project reports. The Kodachrome Slide Project files include correspondence, receipts, reports, educational guides and materials, slide sequences, and printed material.
Printed material includes exhibition catalogs and announcements, clippings, booklets, travel guides, magazines, education journals, subject files on Diego Rivera and Frank Lloyd Wright, and blank postcards from Arquin's travels. There are extensive booklets and pamphlets published by the Pan American Union, and travel guides and educational guides for Latin America. Some printed material is in Spanish.
Photographs include portraits and snapshots of Florence Arquin, Diego Rivera, Frida Kahlo and others. Photos of Florence Arquin show her in her office, giving lectures, and at events with others. Photographs of works of art are by Frida Kahlo and Diego Rivera.
Artwork is scattered and includes a sketchbook by Florence Arquin with watercolor and pencil sketches and a print signed by de Diego.
There are four scrapbooks created by Florence Arquin. Scrapbooks may include photographs, writings, maps, and printed materials. Materials relate to the Federal Art Project at the Art Institute of Chicago, travel, and the Kodachrome Slide Project.
Art Institute of Chicago. -- Faculty; Federal Art Project. (Ill.); Kahlo, Frida; Rebay, Hilla, 1890-1967; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957; United States. Department of State.; Williams, Samuel; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959; Art critics; Art, Latin American; Art--Study and teaching; Authors--Illinois--Chicago; Educators--Illinois--Chicago; Hispanic American art; Painters; Photographers; Photographs; Prints; Sketches; Women artists--Illinois--Chicago
- Biographical Material, 1939-1962; Series 1; 0.4 Linear feet Box 1, 11
  Scope and Contents note
  Found are awards and diplomas, resumes, an ID card, travel papers, and address books. Awards and diplomas include a certificate for a sailfish caught by Arquin in 1942 with a photograph of Arquin and an unidentified woman standing beside the fish, a diploma from the Art Institute of Chicago, and three San Francisco International Color Slide Salon awards. There are ten address books, some of which are organized by country of residence, rather than letter.
  Existence and Location of Copies note
  This series has been scanned in its entirety.
  - Awards, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, F1.
  - Biographical Sketches and Resumes, 1939-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Identification Card, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invitation, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Travel Papers, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes letters of introduction in Spanish, health and vaccine records, and baggage information.
  - Voter Registration, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Address Book, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Address Book, circa 1951-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Address Book, cica 1950 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Address Book, circa 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Oversized Awards, Scanned with Box 1, F1, 1942-1945 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1940-1985; Series 2; 0.8 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Found is Florence Arquin's personal correspondence, including copies of several letters from Diego Rivera in 1946 and 1949 and Frida Kahlo in 1943 and 1952. There is also a 1957 letter written by Arquin, apparently unfinished, recording her reaction to the death of Diego Rivera and some of her memories of their friendship.
  The bulk of the correspondence consists of letters from Arquin to her husband, Samuel Williams. These letters document her trip to Mexico in the early 1940s to paint as well as her role in the Kodachrome Slide Project. They provide insight into her more personal impressions and experiences during this time period. The letters describe the developement of her friendships with Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo, whom she met around 1942. They document Rivera's painting of Arquin's portrait and various meetings and conversations that Arquin had with Rivera and Kahlo. Arquin includes her impressions of Rivera's paintings, his ideas, and his working methods. Additionally, the letters document her friendships with Marc Chagall and Juan O'Gorman, and her relationship with Carlos Mérida. Researchers should note that many of these letters are difficult to date and that although an attempt has been made to arrange them chronologically, this was not always possible and some events described in the letters may appear to be out of sequence.
  The series also contains two folders of Samuel Williams's correspondence.
  - General, 1940-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
    Includes photocopies of letters from Diego Rivera and Frida Kahlo.
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1940 Jun-Jul (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1940 Oct (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1940 Nov (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1942 Jan-Sep (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1942 Oct-Dec (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1943 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1943 Mar-Jul (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1943 Aug-Dec (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1947 Jan-Feb (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1947 Apr-Dec (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, circa 1940-circa 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34-38)
  - Florence Arquin to Samuel Williams, circa 1940-circa 1949 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - Samuel Williams, General Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
- Writings and Notes, 1929-circa 1964; Series 3; 2 Linear feet Box 2-4
  Found are extensive notes including research notes, notebooks, and notecards and titled writings by Florence Arquin. Notes are primarily hand-written and contain research and some background material on a wide variety of subjects, including educational programs developed by Arquin. Titled writings by Arquin include her a draft of her manuscript on Diego Rivera, Diego Rivera (1886-1957): The Shaping of an Artist (Early Period--1889-1921). Writings by others are by Justino Fernández, Jose G. Montes de Oca, Jose de Souza Pedreira, Hilla Rebay, and Diego Rivera.
  - Notebooks (Box 2)
    - Diego Rivera, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Diego Rivera, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 7-13)
    - Diego Rivera, circa 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14-18)
    - Picasso, circa 1945 (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - School, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 21-24)
    - School, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Likely for Kodachrome Slide Project, circa 1950 (Box 2, Folder 26-27)
    - Art, circa 1940-circa 1955 (Box 2, Folder 28-38)
  - Notebooks (Box 3)
    - Notebooks, General, 1959-circa 1964 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Notecards (Box 3)
    - on Art and Architecture, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 4-6)
  - School Writings (Box 3)
    - Assignments and Papers, circa 1929 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Notes, circa 1929 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Outlines, on Picasso and Cezanne, circa 1929 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - Notes (Box 3)
    - Amazonian Archaeology, circa 1940 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Brazilian Art and Architecture, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Catalog, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Churches, circa 1940 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Colonial Art in Latin America, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Contemporary Mexican Painting, circa 1940 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Folk Art in Latin America and Haiti, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Latin American Art and Architecture, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Latin American Churches, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Latin (Native) American Festivals and Dances, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Mayan Art, circa 19540 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Moorish Art, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Picasso, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Rivera, circa 1950-circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 25-31)
    - Sand Paintings, circa 1940 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Spanish Art, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 33-34)
    - General, Art, circa 1940-circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 35-42)
  - Background Material, Latin Native Americans, circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Background Material, Mexican Murals, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Diego Rivera (1886-1957): The Shaping of an Artist (Early Period--1889-1921), by Florence Arquin, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Diego Rivera (1886-1957): The Shaping of an Artist (Early Period--1889-1921), by Florence Arquin, circa 1960 (Box 3, Folder 46-47)
    Draft and List of Illustrations
  - For Museums and Exhibitions, by Florence Arquin, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - "Diego Rivera's Murals," by Florence Arquin, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Three Women Painters in Contemporary Mexican Art," by Florence Arquin, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Notes on 'Day of the Dead' in Mexico," by Florence Arquin, circa 1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Art and Architecture in Latin America, by Florence Arquin, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Cuidad Trujillo, a Filmslide Sequence of Photographic Studies in Color," by Florence Arquin, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Contemporary Popular Art in Haiti," by Florence Arquin, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Diego Rivera, Painter of Mexico: The Story in Paint of One Man's Great Love for his Country, Mexico, and for his Wife, Frida Kahlo," by Florence Arquin, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Bay of All Saints," by Jose de Souza Pedreira, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Nota Sobre las Danzas Mexicanas," by Justino Fernández, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "La Fiesta a la Virgen de los Remedios," by Jose G. Montes de Oca, circa 1950 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "The Beauty of Non-Objectivity," and "The Power of Spiritual Realism," by Hilla Rebay, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Forward, for Florence Arquin's Mexico City Exhibition Catalog, by Diego Rivera, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Writings, in Spanish, 1939-1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Teaching and Project Files, 1930-1963; Series 4; 1.4 Linear feet Box 4-5
  Found are materials relating to Florence Arquin's work teaching at the School of Art Institute of Chicago; her earlier work at the Art Institute's Department of Education with the Federal Art Project; and the Kodachrome Slide Project. Teaching files are scattered and include student papers, course outlines, and a lecture. The Art Institute of Chicago, Department of Education materials include plans, proposals and reports relating to outreach in high schools. Reports include some photographs of exhibitions. Kodachrome Slide Project materials include correspondence, receipts, reports, educational material or teaching guides, drafts of slide sequences, and printed material.
  - Teaching Files, 1934-1959; 4.1
    - Assignments and Student Papers, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Course Outlines, 1934-circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 15-17)
    - Lecture, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, Department of Education, 1939-1944; 4.2
    - Plan, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      For Museum Correlation of Circulation Exhibits in Secondary Schools
    - Project Proposal, circa 1940 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Report on a High School Project, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Report on a High School Project, Supplementary Charts, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Museum Correlation Program in Secondary Schools, Reports, 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
    - Museum Correlation Program in Secondary Schools, Findings from Questionnaire, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "A Brief Study of Similar and Contrasting Characteristics of the Ideologies of Germany and Japan as Reflected in Their Paintings, Posters, Sculpture, etc." by Florence Arquin, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Printed Report, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Kodachrome Slide Project, 1930-1963; 4.3
    - Correspondence, 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, circa 1940-circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Receipts and Invoices, 1943-1957 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Final Report, Part I, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Final Report, Part II, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Educational Material (Box 5)
      - "Toltec Culture of Mexico", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - "Ancient Mayan Culture at Copan", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "South America--The Land", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - "Mining in South America", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - "Indian Life in the Lowlands of South America", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - "Mexican Churches of the Colonial Period", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - "Contemporary Mexican Murals", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Slide Sequence, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Slide Sequence, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Printed Guides, 1930-circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Drafts of Slide Sequences (Box 5)
      - Bolvia, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Brazil, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
      - Peru, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
    - Project Material, Summary, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Printed Guides, circa 1940 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Newsletter, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Printed Material, 1923-1964; Series 5; 1.8 Linear feet Box 5-7, 11
  Found are exhibition announcements and catalogs; magazine and news clippings from both English and Spanish publications; booklets; magazines; tour and travel guides; education journals and guides; museum printed material; subject files on Diego Rivera and Frank Lloyd Wright; blank postcards; and reproductions of works of art. There are extensive booklets and pamphlets produced by the Pan American Union including The Pan American, which include articles written by Arquin. Printed material about Diego Rivera and Frank Lloyd Wright may include catalogs and clippings. Also found is a catalog from an exhibition of Arquin's work in Mexico City (1943) with an introduction by Diego Rivera.
  This series has been partially scanned. In some cases, only covers and relevant pages have been scanned.
  - Exhibition and Lecture Announcements and Catalogs, 1937-1944 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Exhibition and Lecture Announcements and Catalogs, 1945-1961 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Subject Files (Box 5)
    - Diego Rivera, 1933-1938 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Diego Rivera, 1943-1949 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      Includes exhibition catalog for Florence Arquin with foreward written by Diego Rivera.
    - Diego Rivera, 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Diego Rivera, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Diego Rivera, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Diego Rivera, circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      Oversized material housed in Box 11, F5
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, 1934-1948 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Clippings, 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Clippings, 1952-1954 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Clippings, 1956-1962 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Clippings, circa 1930-circa 1950 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    Oversized material housed in Box 11, F6
  - Magazine Articles, 1923-1960 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Magazine Articles, circa 1930-circa 1960 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Pan American Union Publications (Box 5)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol I, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Pan American Union Publications (Box 6)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol III, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol IV, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol VII, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol VIII, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol IX, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - The Good Neighbor Tour, Vol X, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Travel Brochures, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - The Pan American Union issues, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Guides, Bulletins, and Newsletters, circa 1923-1948 (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
  - Mexican Folkways Issues, 1927-1937 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - The Lamp Issues, 1943-1945 (Box 6, Folder 15-16)
  - This Week--Este Semana Issues, 1942-1958 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Good Neighbor Series Issues, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Education Leaflets, Guides, and Journals, 1929-1944 (Box 6, Folder 20-22)
  - Education Guides, Latin America, circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 23-24)
  - Travel Guides, 1938-1942 (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
  - Museum Guides and Newsletters, 1944-circa 1950 (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
  - United Nations Publications, circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Federal Art Project Publications, 1937-1939 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Material Written by Robert C. Smith, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Magazines and Journals, 1944-1949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Spanish Language Publications, 1935-circa 1950 (Box 7, Folder 5-7)